We will not walk in fear of one another.
Good Night, and Good Luck. is a drama, history film directed by George Clooney.
The story of journalist Edward R.
Murrow's stand against Senator Joseph McCarthy's
anti-communist witch-hunts in the early 1950s.
Edward R. Murrow, played by David Strathairn.
Shirley Wershba, played by Patricia Clarkson.
Fred Friendly, played by George Clooney.
Sig Mickelson, played by Jeff Daniels.
Joe Wershba, played by Robert Downey Jr..
William Paley, played by Frank Langella.
Good Night, and Good Luck (stylized as good night, and good luck.) is a 2005 historical drama
film directed by George Clooney from a screenplay by Clooney and Grant Heslov.
It stars David Strathairn, Patricia Clarkson, George
Clooney, Jeff Daniels, Robert Downey Jr.
and Frank Langella, and portrays the conflict
between veteran journalist Edward R.
Murrow (Strathairn) and U.S.
Senator Joseph McCarthy of Wisconsin, especially relating to the anti-communist
Senator's actions with the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations.
Although released in black and white, it was filmed on color film stock, but on a
grayscale set, and was color-corrected to black and white during post-production.
It focuses on the theme of media responsibility, and
also addresses what occurs when U.S.
journalism offer voices of dissent from government policy.
The movie takes its title (which ends with a period or full stop) from the
line with which Murrow routinely signed off his broadcasts.
The film was a box office success and received critical acclaim for Clooney's direction, the
writing, cinematography, production design and performances (particularly Strathairn's).
It was nominated for six Academy Awards, including Best
Picture, Best Director and Best Actor for Strathairn.
The film explores themes of government, telecaster, political
activism, politician, based on true story.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.